Jillian K. FitzMaurice

Denver, CO 80231 | (303)901-3230 | fitzmauricejillian@gmail.com LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/jillianfitzmaurice100

GitHub: https://github.com/ShyFidelity | Portfolio: https://shyfidelity.online/

Summary

Front-end developer with a bachelor's degree in fine art. A recent graduate of Denver University's Full Stack Web Development program and pursuing AWS Cloud certification. Committed to finding an innovative user experience by challenging the status quo with conceptual and creative thinking. Excels at working with teams with an openness to new solutions and a broad spectrum of voices. A firm believer that morale, empathy, and integrity are necessary for keeping any good team both light and on task.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, ES6

Libraries + Tools: React.js, Git, Express, MERN, Bootstrap, Materialize, MUI, jQuery **Competencies:** User Authentication, Responsive Design, MVC, Node.js, Technical eloquence **Applications:** GitHub, Heroku, MongoDB, MySQL, Visual Studio Code, Adobe CS, Figma

Projects

Friends of Toto | https://github.com/shyfidelity | https://friendsoftoto.herokuapp.com/
"A social network for pets because people talk too much" A Deployed MERN stack application

that allows user to user connections and the ability to create new posts and upload photos.

- Collaborated with a team to design, implement, and deploy this application
- Incorporated Amazon's S3 bucket for photo upload and storage
- Front end developer and designer ensuring that the UI was user friendly with solid design and implementation using both CSS and MUI framework
- Created all graphics and visual elements in Adobe Illustrator

Frontend -HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Web Components, React.js

Backend - AWS, GraphQL, Node.js, Express, Apollo

Ouroboros | https://github.com/ShyFidelity/Ouroboros | https://ouroboros-ml-jf-ni.herokuapp.com/ Ouroboros is a social wellness app designed to track a user's progress on activities known to increase dopamine and serotonin in the brain.

- Coordinated a team using wireframes, Kanban board, and prototypes
- Created a loop reward system to ensure daily patterns and user satisfaction
- Set up AWS server to store user profile information
- Created SVG animations and "badges" with Adobe Illustrator and After Effects
- Front end javascript developer

Frontend -HTML5, CSS, Flexbox, Javascript, Handlebars

Backend - AWS, MySQL, Node.Js, Express, third party APIs

Experience

Ivy Nails January 2022 - present

Freelance Developer https://github.com/ShyFidelity/ivy | https://shyfidelity.github.io/ivy/

Denver, Co

In progress first freelance web application for local nail salon.

- Worked directly with the client to implement design ideas, gather content, as well as encourage ways it would increase her revenue
- Developed and designed a mobile responsive React app
- Created all graphic elements

Frontend - React.js, CSS, React Bootstrap, Koalendar scheduling software

Code Sensi July 2021 - present

Code Ninjas Denver, CO

Worked in a team environment to teach kids 4-14 years old the foundations of JavaScript while building video games. Students gained problem-solving, critical thinking, and STEM skills in a fun, safe, and inspiring environment.

Key Accomplishments:

- Recommended by management to mentor and motivate advanced students in a 1:1 setting to build web applications
- Recognized for finding new creative ways to help students achieve their goals faster

Production Manager // Designer

February 2013 - January 2022

The Woods Fine Jewelry

Denver, CO

Designed jewelry with attention to detail. Managed inventory for wholesale accounts with retailers throughout the US.

Key Accomplishments:

- Constantly stay up to date with designs with a turnaround time as short as one day
- Implemented a simple inventory system from hard paper copies to Excel, resulting in a 10% decrease in loss the first month
- Researched previous sales and current design trends to maximize profits
- Maintained client relationships with 20+ stores as well as clients such as The Bachelorette, and The Kardashians, and various award shows

Education

Certificate in Full Stack Web. Development: Denver University, Denver, CO December 2021 A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Reactjs, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, NoSQL, MongoDB, & Express Bachelor of Fine Art: Milwaukee Institute of Art and Design, Denver, CO May 2013 Study Abroad Program: Burren College of Art Ballyvaughan, Ireland May 2012